We cannot meditate
我們不能做靜坐
we only can be in meditation
只能入靜
When we say we are going to meditate
當我們說我們要靜坐
it has no meaning
這是毫無意義的
We have to be in meditation
我們要在入靜中
Either you are inside the house or outside the house
你不是在屋內就是在屋外
You cannot be inside the house and then say that: “Now I’m outside the house.”
你不能在屋內說 我現在在屋外
Or when you are outside the house you cannot say: “I’m inside the house.”
又或當你在屋外 你不能說 我在屋內
In the same way
同樣
you are moving in three dimensions of your life
我們 你向著生命的三個面向前進
– of emotional and physical and mental being
情緒 肉身和思維的存在體
You are not inside yourself.
你並不在你之內
But when you are inside that you are in thoughtless awareness.
一旦你在內在 就能處於無思慮的覺醒狀態
Then, not only that you are there
你不謹在哪裡
but you are everywhere
還無處不在
because that is the place
因為就是那地方
that is the point where you are really in universal…
那裡你才真的身處宇宙
From there you are in contact with the Principle
那裡你與原理 與力量(Shakti)
with the Shakti, with the Power that permeates into every particle
與滲透入物質的 每一個微粒的力量連上
that is matter , into every thought that is emotion
你滲入每一個思緒
into every planning and thinking of the whole world.
滲入全世界每一項計劃和想法
You permeate into all the elements that have created this beautiful Earth
每一個創造這個美麗地球的元素
You permeate into earth
你滲入地球
you permeate into Akasha [sky, ether]
滲入Akasha (印地語/梵文即天空/以太)
into teja [light]
滲入Teja(即光)
into sound
滲入聲音
But your movement is very slow.
你的動作很緩慢
Then you say: “I’m meditating,”
接著你說 我在靜坐冥想
that means you are moving in permeation with the Universal Being
即是說你與宇宙存在體 一起移動滲透
But you are not moving yourself
你不是自己移動
you are just unloading yourself to be free
而是放下身上的包袱
from the weight of things that do not allow you to move
把不容許你移動的重物放下
When you are in meditation you must allow yourself to be in thoughtless awareness
當你入靜 你要讓自己 處於無思無慮的知覺狀態
There, the Unconscious Itself, the Achetana itself will take charge of you
在這個狀態 無意識 Achetana 會接管
You will start moving with the force of Achetana.
你開始與Atita (即超越)力量一起移動
The Unconscious is going to work it out.
無意識自會把它成就
It is going to take you there, where It wants you to go
它會帶你到哪裡 它也想你到哪裡
You keep to thoughtless awareness all the time.
每時每刻 你都處於無思無慮的知覺狀態
Try to keep to thoughtless awareness as much as you can.
你要盡量保持在這個狀態
When you are in thoughtless awareness
當你在無思無慮的知覺狀態
you must know that you are in the Kingdom of God
你必須知道 自己已在天國裡
and His people , His arrangements, His consciousness
祂的子民 祂的各種安排 祂的意識
is going to look after you.
都會照顧你
Even when you are giving vibrations to other people
即使當你給別人生命能量
I have noticed that you are not in thoughtless awareness.
我發覺你也不在 無思無慮知覺狀態
If you give vibrations in thoughtless awareness
若你在無思無慮知覺狀態下 給人生命能量
you will not catch anything
就不會有任何感染
because all these entities that enter into you
因為所有進入你的存在體
all these material problems that come into you
所有你的物質問題
come when you are in those three dimensions.
都是因為你處於這三個面向
Through Sahaja Yoga
透過霎哈嘉瑜伽
you have opened your gates of your own being.
你開啟了你存在體的大門
You have entered into your own kingdom
你進入了自己的王國
but you do not keep there.
但你仍沒有留下來
You come out of it
你走出來
and again you go back and settle down – doesn’t matter
再回去 然後安頓下來 不要緊
You should not feel so disappointed about it, so frustrated.
你不應為此感到失望沮喪
You know people have worked for thousands of years
你知道人們為此 已經工作了數千年
and they could not separate themselves from themselves
他們仍未能把自己從自己分隔開
Only you people, the Sahaja Yogis
只有你們 霎哈嘉瑜伽士
whom are made after the pattern of Shri Ganesh himself
你們是從格涅沙的模式創造出來
are so powerful
你們是那麽有力量
that they can give awakening and realisation to other people.
能喚醒別人 給人自覺
Even if you are caught up, you have seen you have powers.
即使你受感染 你已經看到自己擁有力量
Even if you feel that the vibrations are not coming
即使你仍未感到生命能量
you know you have powers.
你知道自己擁有力量
You can give realisations to others.
能給人自覺
In your presence people get realisation
你的出現就能令人有自覺
But you have to be that power completely.
但你要完全成為這個力量
Supposing there’s something wrong with your car
就如你的車子出毛病
: But as long as it is moving
只要它仍能動
it’s alright.
仍是妥當的
You have to repair it.
你要把它修好
You have to repair all the time all our moods
你要每時每刻修補自己的情緒
which we have caused ourselves by our foolishness
你有情緒是源於你的愚昧
by our lust, by our greed
你的欲望 你的貪婪
by so many false identifications we carried with ourselves.
和很多對自己虛假的認同
We must have a complete attention towards our weaknesses
我們要把注意力 完全放在自己的弱點
and not towards our achievements.
而不是成就上
If we know what are our weaknesses it’s better
若我們知道自己的弱點 就更好
that we can really swim across better.
那麽我們就能好好游過超越它
Supposing, on a ship there is a hole
就如船上有個小洞
and the water is coming in through that hole
海水從這個小洞湧進來
the attention of all the crew, of all the staff
所有船員 所有職員
and the captain itself will be on that hole from where the water is coming in, and nowhere else.
船長都會把注意力 放在這個有水湧進來的小洞
In the same way, you must be on the watch-out.
同樣 你也要當心
There are so many pitfalls for a Sahaja Yogi – I have seen it.
有很多針對霎哈嘉瑜伽士的陷井 我曾經見過
Of course, even the past is over
當然 即使過去已經完結
even the past can be overcome.
已經克服
In the present also they have many shadows of the past working.
在當下 仍有很多過去的陰影
For example, when you are sitting in a group
例如 當你坐在一羣人裡
you are involved with each other.
你們互相牽引纏繞
Those who are involved with each other
互相牽引纏繞的人
by any relationship whatsoever
不管是什麽關係
must know that this kind of involvement
你們必須知道 這種牽引纏繞
is not going to help them to attain their individual ascent.
不會對昇進有任何幫助
Everybody is ascending individually though you are collectively contacted with each other
每個人都是獨自昇進 雖然你們都集體地與大家有聯繫
and in communication;
有溝通
but the ascendance is individual
昇進卻是個人的事
absolutely individual.
絶對是個人的事
So whether he is your son, brother, sister, wife, friend
所以不管他是你的兒子 你的兄弟 你的姊妹 你的妻子 你的朋友
you must remember that you are not responsible for their ascendance.
要緊記 你不需要對他們的昇進負責
You cannot help them for their ascendance.
你不能幫助他們昇進
Only Mother’s Grace and their own desire
他們的昇進 只能透過母親的恩典 他們自己的欲望
their own effort, to give up all that
自己的努力去放棄屬於
is three dimensional will help them.
三個面向的東西 (情緒 肉身 思維)才能幫到他們
So whenever a thought comes like that
所以一旦你有這種思維
you must know that you have not attained the thoughtless awareness in its full extent
就知道自己還未完全到達 無思無慮的覺醒狀態
and that’s how you have problems
這就是為何你仍出問題
which are three-dimensional.
三個面向的問題
Sometimes, a Sahaja Yogi will find
有時 霎哈嘉瑜伽士發覺
an emotion will come into his mind.
有種情緒進入他的腦袋
It will be an emotion of dejection or frustration
是沮喪或挫敗的感覺
and he will be disgusted with himself or with others.
他們會對自己或對別人感到厭惡
Both things are just the same
兩者都是如出一轍
I have seen some Sahaja Yogis get very disgusted with others.
我曾經見過 有些霎哈嘉瑜伽士很厭惡別人
There should be no disgust that is lasting.
不應有任何持續的厭惡感
Of course, for a short time
當然 一段短時間
you might feel a disgust. It’s alright. It’s a passing phase
你或許會感到厭惡 這還可以 這是必經階段
Or you might feel disgusted with yourself –
又或你討厭自己
may be a passing phase.
或許這是過度的階段
But if you go on hankering on to it
但若你持續有這種感覺
or if you go on clinging to it
或你黏貼這種感覺
that means you are conditioning yourself
即是說你為自己設定限制
that means you are not in thoughtless awareness
亦是說你不在無思無慮的知覺中
that means that you are in your past
你是在過去
you are making your past a solid mass on your head.
你讓過去密密麻麻的 放進你的腦袋裡
In the present everything is fleeting.
在當下 一切都是短暫飛逝的
Everything is fleeting that is not eternal
一切短暫飛逝的就是不永恆
In the present the eternal stays
在當下 永恆留下
the rest all drops out
其餘都會消退
It’s like a moving river which doesn’t stop anywhere
就像流動的河流 它不會停在任何地方
But the moving river is eternal.
流動的河流是永恆的
The rest of the things are all changing.
其餘的東西都在改變
If you are on the Eternal Principle
若你在永恆的原理上
all that is not eternal changes
一切不永恆都在改變
and drops out
在消退
dissolves and becomes nonexistent.
在分解 不再存在
We have to understand our own dignity
我們要明白自己的尊嚴
our own essence.
自己的本質
The first and foremost is that all the Sahaja Yogis are the chosen ones
首要的是所有霎哈嘉瑜伽士 都是被揀選的一羣
They are the people whom God has chosen
是神揀選他們
In this city of Delhi there are thousands and thousands of people.
在德里這個城市 有成千上萬的人口
All over the world there are so many people that we are suffering from overpopulation
全世界都在受人口過剩之苦
but in Sahaja Yoga there are very, very few people.
但霎哈嘉瑜伽卻很少很少人
And when you are chosen
一旦你被揀選
the first, you must also realise that you are the foundations.
你要知道自己是根基
You are the stones that are to be laid down
是要建立的基石
and have to be strong
你要強壯
have to be forbearing
要克制忍耐
and that’s why it is necessary that all of you who are now few
這就是為何你們這些少數人
who are the first lamps
這些要點亮開悟
that are going to enlighten other lamps in the world
全世界其他燈的第一盞燈
you have to enjoy the strength of eternity
有必要享受永恆的力量
the strength of Divine Love
享受上天愛的力量
the strength of this Universal Being that you are.
享受你是宇宙存在體的力量
This is what meditation is.
這就是靜坐
So when Sahaja Yogis ask me:
所以當霎哈嘉瑜伽士問我
“What should we do for meditation?”
我們靜坐該做什麽
You be in thoughtless awareness that’s all
你要在無思無慮的覺醒中 就這樣
Don’t do anything.
不要做什麽
At that time, not [only] that you are moving towards the goal
那時刻 你向著目標
or that the Unconscious is taking charge of you
又或無意識掌管著你
not only that, but also that you are emitting
不謹如此 你還在散發
for the first time
第一次
the Divine into the nature
把上天散發進大自然
into your surroundings
散發進你的四周
into other people
散發進所有與你連上的人
Only thing is that we are used to one thing
唯一你要做的是
that is we must do something about it
我們要做點事
and so that’s why we start doing something
这就是为什么我们要做些事
Meditation is the most Sahaja method.
靜坐是最自然的方法
Then we have prayers and we have also puja.
接著我們禱告 也有崇拜
Prayers are also
禱告也
if said in your heart
若你真心的
with the feeling of complete surrendering
完全順服委身的禱告
and asking for the Eternal
請求永恆
it will be granted.
就會賜予給你
Just ask for that and the rest will take [you] step-by-step.
只要請求 其餘的事情 都會受到照顧 一步一步
All the Sahaja Yogis have a problem.
所有霎哈嘉瑜伽士都有問題
And they have problems because of their past
問題出在他們的過去
because of their future aspirations.
也出在他們對未來的渴求
Now when you have problems
現在當你出問題
in Sahaja Yoga you have learnt how to overcome them.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽 你已經學懂怎樣克服它們
There are so many methods other than meditation
除了靜坐 還有很多其他方法
you know them very well that
你知道得很清楚
you must know what is the chakra where the Kundalini is.
你必須知道什麽是輪穴 靈量在那裡
Now, if the Kundalini has been stopped
若靈量的上昇 受某個不能運作的輪穴阻塞
you shouldn’t get frustrated about it.
不要感到沮喪
Supposing your instrument or your car has stopped on the way
就如你的器具 或你的車子在路中停了
what’s the use of getting frustrated with it?
只感到沮喪挫敗有什麽用呢
You have to learn the mechanism
你要學懂所有機械運作
You have to be a good technician
要成為好的技術員
and then you can manage it very well
那麽你就能好好處理它
So all the techniques of Sahaja Yoga must be learned and mastered
所以必須學習和掌握 霎哈嘉瑜伽的技術
This you can only do by giving it to others
你唯一要做的是 把這些技術給予別人
and learning from correcting them and correcting yourself.
學習糾正他們 糾正自己
There is nothing to be frustrated.
不用有挫敗感
That’s the worst thing.
這是最差勁的
If you get frustrated
若你感到挫敗
and unhappy with yourself
對自己不高興
then there is going to be a problem.
就會出問題
You have to laugh at yourself
你要取笑自己
and laugh at your mechanism that is out of gear
取笑你故障的機件
When you start identifying yourself even with the instrument
當你開始認同於自己 即使認同自己是器具
then you are not there
你就不在那裡
You are not the chakras
你不是輪穴
you are not the different channels
不是不同的經脈
You are the awareness
你是意識
you are the power, you are the Kundalini
你是力量 你是靈量
So you don’t have to worry about all these things being not in their proper conditions
所以不用擔憂輪穴經脈 不在恰當的狀態
If they are not, you can solve it.
若它們不在狀態 你能解決
Just now the lights went off
就在現在 沒有了燈光
If the lights have went off because of the electricity failure
若是因為電力出問題
it’s a serious thing.
這是嚴重的問題
But if the lights have gone out because there is a fused bulb
但若沒有光是因為燈泡壞了
oh, you can replace it, you can do all that.
你可以把燈泡換掉 你們全都能做到
So there is no need to worry if your chakras are spoilt.
若你的輪穴有阻塞 不用擔憂
Worrying itself, or frustrating yourself
亦不用感到沮喪
itself is a wrong attitude towards Sahaja Yoga
霎哈嘉瑜伽士有這種態度是錯的
‘Sahaja’, in other terminology also means
霎哈嘉(Sahaja)這個詞彙 另一個意思是
is ‘a simple thing’.
是簡單
‘Sahaja’means to be Sahaja means in
霎哈嘉的意思 要霎哈嘉是
I can say how Tulsidas (Kabir) has said:
我告訴你杜勒西達斯 (Tulsidas古印度詩人)曾說
“Jaise rakha hu taise hi rahu” [You keep me as you like].
Jaise rakha hu taise hi rahu (你喜歡就保留我吧)
That kind of an attitude takes your attention inside
這種態度就能 把你的注意力帶進內在
because outside it is let alone , to the dogs;
外面就留給狗兒吧
let alone
留給
We are not bothered about the outside part.
我們不在意外在
“As you keep me, I will be, in that manner”.
你們 我會以這種態度
And you will be surprised everything clicks out very well.
你會很驚訝 一切忽然明白過來
Even, sometimes, you might feel:
即使 有時 你或許感到
“I should reach a certain place”,
我要到某個地方
“I must have this bhajan done”,
我要把Bhajan 辦妥
“I must get these things done”
我要把這些事情辦好
and it’s not done sometimes.
有時事情未能做妥當
Sometimes by mistake something as you want is not done.
有時陰錯陽差 你想做好的事情卻未能做好
You must accept it as the will of God.
你要接受這是神的旨意
That is what He desires. It’s alright.
是祂的欲望 還可以
That is the desire of God
這是神的欲望
and now you are one with His desire.
你現在與祂的欲望一致
You are here to communicate the desire of God to the whole world
你在這裡是要向全世界 表達溝通神的欲望
and, at this stage
在…在這個階段
if you start having your own desires
若你開始有自己的欲望
and ideas about yourself
自己的想法
then, when will you become the desire of God?
那麽什麽時候 你才能變成神的欲望
This ‘I-ness’ has to go away.
這個 我 必須離去
That is what meditation is.
這就是靜坐
Where you are no more ‘I’ but it is ‘You’.
靜坐是 我 不再存在 只有 你
Kabirdasji has written a beautiful poem about it
伽比爾(Kabirdasji) 曾寫過關於靜坐美麗的詩歌
that, when the goat is living and [kicking?],
當羊活生生跳動時
she says: “Mai, mai”, that is “I, I”.
會叫 Mein mein( 咩、咩) 這就是 我
But then she dies
羊死後
and her intestines are drawn out into wires
拿出牠的腸子 拉成直線
and some saint fixes them on the “tutari”,
有些聖人把它們固定在Tutari上
that instrument that they have
Tutari是一種 他們稱為Ektari的器具
And he goes on pulling it with his fingers
而他不停的用手指拉腸子
then it says: “Tuhi, Tuhi, Tuhi,”
腸子就發出 Tu hi Tu hi Tu hi 的聲音
that is: “You are, You are, You are”.
這是 你是 你是 你是
That is how we have to die
這就是為何我們要死去
and we have to be resurrected.
要復活重生
You have been already
你們已經做到
but Sahaja yoga as I have told you
我已經告訴過你 霎哈嘉瑜伽是Kheer
or what you call
即你在陶鍋裡煮的甜品
“Kachche ghade ki kheer hai [kheer cooked in clay pot].
Kachche ghade ki kheer hai
So the soil of the raw pot also is mixed up.
因此與陶鍋裡的泥土混合起來
But your attention can be with the kheer, with the milk
你的注意力可以放在Kheer上 放在牛奶上
and can drop out all that is the mud of the raw pot.
把陶鍋裡的泥土全都去掉
That discrimination is spontaneous.
這種明辨能力是自然而然的
It is there.
就在這裡
You have got it: self-actualisation.
你已經取得 自我實現
You can feel yourself.
你能感覺自己
You know you are not that.
你知道自己不是這樣
You have started talking about your chakras in the same manner.
以同樣的態度 你已經開始談論你的輪穴
But the only thing
唯一的是
the only problem, or the only defect
唯一的問題是 或唯一霎哈嘉瑜伽士的缺點
that, still, though he is there
仍然是以為自己在這裡
his attention is involved with outside.
他的注意力仍被外在牽引著
That’s the only defect.
這是唯一的缺點
If the attention is removed…
若把注意力移走
how to remove? That’s the point.
怎樣移走 這是重點
That is the first thing.
這是首要的
Once you say, “how to remove?”
一旦你說 怎樣移走
means you have created the three-dimensional involvement.
即是說你已經創造了 三個面向的牽引
You are not to remove. It is [already] there!
你不是去移走 它就在這裡
If your attention is outside
若你的注意力在外
then I would have said: “No, your attention has to go inside
我就要說 不 你的注意力要放在內在
It has not got yet.”
你仍未取得它
But it is there. You are sitting there.
它就在這裡 你坐在這裡
I am sitting here.
我也坐在這裡
But my attention is outside.
但我的注意力卻在外
I have to just feel myself where I am, that’s all.
我要感覺自己身在何方 就這樣
Some have felt it
有些人感覺到
some have achieved it.
有些人成就到
You know among yourselves
你們知道 你們之中
there are some who have gone very high up.
有些人已經昇進得很高
The other method we employ is of puja.
另一個方法是崇拜
I’ve found that works very well with human beings – puja –
我發覺崇拜對人類大有幫助
because it satisfies lots of demands of the past habits
因為它能滿足很多過往的習慣
that you feel that you are doing something about it.
你感到你在做過往的事情
Then you start giving whatever you think God has given you – the blessings.
你開始給予你認為神 給予你的東西 祝福
And the Rishi and Muni have found out
惠和木已經發現
they’re very clever people
他們都是聰明人
they have found out how to please the Deities
他們發現怎樣取悅神祇
how to please the Mother.
怎樣取悅母親
So they have told you
所以他們已經告訴你
as they have told you even in this lifetime of mine
他們告訴你即使在我這一生
how to please Her.
怎樣取悅她
They say She is Stutipriya
他們說 她 是Stutipriya
that means ‘She likes praises’.
意思是她喜歡受讚美
It’s not that.
不是這樣的
But when you praise someone from the heart
當你真心的讚美任何人
that means you are accepting it
即是說你接受他
and that is the time the chakras start creating a force by which you are thrown
就在這時候 輪穴開始創造一種動力
you are triggered, into that realm of God.
你因此被抛進 被激發進入神的國度
So these puja methods and prayer methods and the mantra methods
崇拜 禱告 唸口訣這些方法
have been devised and found out by great thinkers of Sahaja Yoga
都是霎哈嘉瑜伽偉大的思想家
the great masters of Sahaja Yoga.
偉大的導師設計和發現出來
And it is the effort
這是霎哈嘉瑜伽士的努力
or you can say the effortless effort
或可以說不用花力氣
of the Sahaja yogis that makes my body vibrate
令你的身體有生命能量
extracts the essence from my body, I should say.
我應說是從你的身體抽取精華
They make, it makes, the Infinite release Itself through this finite being.
他們令 它令無限透過有限的 存在體釋放出來
And it works, it clicks, I have seen it, it works out very well.
它成就到 它恍然大悟 我曾經見過 它成就得很好
But you know that, after puja
但你也知道 崇拜後
I get little tired
我有點倦
because, if you cannot receive it, that Force
因為若你不吸收它 吸收這個大能
I want to sleep
我想睡覺
and get rid of that additional vibrations into “sushupti” [deep sleep] by entering into the Infinite State.
新增的生命能量擺脫到Sushupti 讓它進入無限的狀態
If you could receive whatever I am emitting
在崇拜裡 若你能吸收我釋放的能量
in balance, with your puja
處於平衡
then only it helps better.
就更有幫助
That means, when you are doing puja also, receive it.
意思是當你做崇拜 也在吸收能量
Be in thoughtless awareness when you are doing puja
崇拜時要處於 無思無慮的覺醒狀態
completely concentrated in receiving.
完全集中精神吸收生命能量
But while [doing] puja people are talking.
人們卻在崇拜中交談
I’ve seen that they’re moving about. I mean, I don’t know how to explain it!
我曾經見過 他們 四處走動 我是說 我不知怎樣解釋
That’s the time something is oozing out, the nectar
那時刻有些東西在慢慢滲透 蜜液
and you just receive it at that time with full devotion.
那時刻 你只要以完全順服奉獻的心吸收它
It is oozing out.
它在慢慢滲透
If you feel my vibrations of my chakras at that time
若你感到我的生命能量 那時候我輪穴的生命能量
you will realise
你會知道
that even the minute, small little
即使是一分鐘 細微的
wheels in my body are moving at different spaces
我身體的輪穴在不同空間
at different speed
不同速度
at different dimension.
不同面向移動
And I really don’t know how to explain! But, you see, it creates a melody.
我真的不懂怎樣解釋 但你看到它創造了一種韻律
You have to receive it and it is a melody individually
你要吸收它 它是個別的音韻
suitable for every individual.
適合每一個人
And when you receive it
當你吸收它
it triggers in you that state of infinity.
它就在你身上激發無限的狀態
So at the time of puja
所以在崇拜時
you must know that all your attention should be in reception.
你必須知道你 你全部注意力都要在迎接它
Today is a very great day with the New Year.
今天新年是個大日子
Within two years from today
兩年之內
Satya Yuga is going to start.
完滿期(Satyayuga)要開展
It’s a great day for many things
對很多事情而言 這是個大日子
that nine days are celebrated after this
年之後九天也要慶祝
for the advent of Mother.
母親的降世
It is the date
就是這日子
or I should say, the calendar was started by my forefathers
我要說 日曆是由我祖先開展
and they perceived
他們察覺
that this is the day when the Mother started creating.
這天母親開始創造
And this is the day She created Ganesha to begin with.
首先 她創造了格涅沙
In the Utpatti stage [first stage, Genesis],
在Utpatti階段
She started her work this day.
她這天開展她的工作
And that’s why they put this date as the first date
因此他們視這天為第一天
because the time started from this date long time back.
因為很久以前 時間是從這天開始
And that’s why this date is very important
所以這天很重要
and if you cross this date then you are beyond time.
若你超越這天 你就超越時間
You have to step on to this date and go beyond.
你要踏在這天之上 超越它
You have to step on your dharma
你要站在正法
on to your religion, and go beyond : ‘dharmateet’.
站在宗教上 超越它們Dharmateet
You have to be those three gunas
你要成為這三種狀態(Gunas)
and to go beyond : ‘gunateet’.
超越它 Gunateet
You are all those three.
你們全是這三種狀態
But the steps on which you are standing have to be all right
但你踏著的路徑必須正確
or those which are crossed or, have to be all right too.
或超越的路徑 必須也要正確
So when you are beyond
一旦你超越
you have to repair those steps, which you have crossed somehow
你要修補這些梯級 不管如何
which can be done through meditation, puja, prayers.
你已經穿越了 可以透過靜坐 崇拜 禱告做到
But the most important
最重要
the greatest advancement is done
最了不起的進步
by giving the universal through your universal being.
是透過你宇宙的存在體成就到
You all must dedicate your life to Sahaja Yoga
你們全都要把你的人生 獻給霎哈嘉瑜伽
and give more and more.
付出更多更多
Among us there are some people
我們之中有些人
who have given a lot
已經付出很多
and by that they have achieved a lot too.
因此他們也有很大的成就
You have to give, talk about it, spread it
你要付出 談及它 傳播它
and bring more people to get this.
帶更多人來得到自覺
Otherwise they will be left out of evolutionary processes.
不然他們會在進化過程中 被遺留下來
There’s no time for you to doubt and think;
你已經沒時間去懷疑和思考
don’t waste your time in all these useless activities.
不要浪費時間 在這些無用的活動上
If you have still doubts, it’s better to give up.
若你仍有疑惑 最好還是放棄吧
It’s high time that you get into the process.
你應立即就進入這個過程
So today I wish you happy New Year for a journey in the spiritual life of this world.
今天 我希望你能在這個世界的 靈性生命中有個快樂的新年旅程
You have to think of all the Sahaja Yogis
你要想及所有
who are far away from us
遠離我們的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
and our thoughts should carry our love for them
我們的思緒要把愛帶給他們
and they should be blessed as you all are blessed here.
他們也應如你們在這裡一樣 受到祝福
I hope these important days that I am here
我希望在這些重要的日子 我在這裡
you will fully dedicate yourself
就如我告訴你
for your emancipation on those four lines
把自己完全奉獻在解放自己上
And whatever program comes in, take it sahaj.
不管有什麽節目 要以霎哈嘉的態度來接受
You should not insist on times and timings.
你不應堅持 要有怎樣的時間和時機
Whatever comes sahaaj, accept it.
不管什麽自然(霎哈嘉)而來 只要接受它吧
May God bless you.
願神祝福你們